Peter Preston

Sr Back-End Developer | Python, JavaScript | AWS, Azure

superengineer127@gmail.com

Q Vienna, Austria

SUMMARY

Dedicated and driven full-stack software engineer with specialized skills in web development.

Having extensive experience building industrial web applications from scratch to production for a variety of industries including healthcare, internet marketing, entertainment, live streaming, and blockchain/web3.

Having a special passion for OpenAl/ChatGPT and GPT variants and other Al services, and has rich experience in integrating services to build intelligent platforms.

Have been working on remote teams for the past 6 years and am a good team player.

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016

 Bachelor's degree of Computer Science University of Vienna

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

01/2021 - 11/2023

Full-stack Engineer

FataSoft

- Handled the Web3 integration for different wallet connections and contract integrations for multi-chain support, including Ethereum, Binance, Polygon, etc.
- · Rebuilt the Vue.js front-end application in Vue3, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS.
- Built a Node.js and TypeScript back-end for handling transaction reports, billing reports, invoicing systems, and more for crypto partners.
- · Utilized Firebase, Firestore, GCP (Big Query, Pub-Sub) handling for database and DevOps.

01/2018 - 12/2021

Full Stack Software Engineer

Dynatrace

- · Built cybersecurity web app using React .
- Designed and developed the components and architect underlying systems.
- · Consumed and integrated GraphQL API.
- · Defined problems, collected data, established facts and validated conclusions.
- Performed Website tests accorded to planned schedules, and after any Web site and product revision.
- · Conferred with management to prioritize needs, resolve conflicts and develop content criteria.

12/2016 - 12/2018

Full Stack Developer

Bitpanda

- Created a Firebase cloud-function back end with Node.js for the Ellipsis mobile app and web dashboards.
- · Built a front-end visualization dashboard with Vue.js, chart.js, and D3.
- · Constructed an automatic voice call center using Twilio and Node.js together with an NLP API.
- Created a React front-end admin dashboard for complex table data visualization with userfriendly search features.
- Used Google Cloud Platform heavily, namely Google Storage, BigQuery, Speech-to-Text API, and Firebase

LANGUAGES

English Native



SKILLS

Python / Django / Flask / FastAPI JavaScript React / Redux / React Hooks Next.js Gatsby

MySQL / PostgreSQL / AWS RDS Data API / AWS DynamoDB AWS / Azure / GCP Blockchain / Web 3

ElasticSearch / AWS OpenSearch Git / GitHub / GitLab / BitBucket Jira / Trello